<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Android | Steven Chen]]></title>
  <link href="http://xuanxi.github.io/blog/categories/android/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://xuanxi.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-15T11:55:42+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://xuanxi.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Steven Chen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[置顶]官方文档阅读与总结]]></title>
    <link href="http://xuanxi.github.io/blog/2014/07/15/guan-fang-wen-dang-yue-du-yu-zong-jie/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-15T10:33:22+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://xuanxi.github.io/blog/2014/07/15/guan-fang-wen-dang-yue-du-yu-zong-jie</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>理解官方指南是每一位Android工程师技术进阶的必经之路，可惜很多人（包括我）并没有真正重视起来。随着开发工作的深入，我决定开始认真研读，以下为所读文章的摘录、翻译和笔记，若有理解偏差的地方，欢迎大家批评指正。</p>

<h2>设计指南-Design</h2>

<p>也许有人会说Design只是设计师的工作，对此我并不反对，但我认为作为一位合格的Android工程师必须首先理解Android Design，这样才能更好地配合设计师开发出实用美观的作品。</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.xuanxi.me/blog/2014/07/13/android-design-principles/">Android Design Principles</a><br/>
Android设计准则。每一个新的Android应用都应该尽量基于这些准则去设计。另外，平时使用各种应用的时候也应该关注其设计的好坏，结合Android设计准则进行分析，逐渐加深自己对用户体验的理解。</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.xuanxi.me/blog/2014/07/15/phones-and-tablets/">Phones &amp; Tablets</a><br/>
Android在手机和平板上的界面框架。<br/>
可以对比iOS中的<a href="http://blog.xuanxi.me/blog/2014/07/15/bars/">Status Bar and Navigation Bar</a></p>

<h2>开发指南-Develop</h2>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phones &amp; Tablets]]></title>
    <link href="http://xuanxi.github.io/blog/2014/07/15/phones-and-tablets/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-15T10:13:23+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://xuanxi.github.io/blog/2014/07/15/phones-and-tablets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>原文地址：<a href="http://developer.android.com/design/handhelds/index.html">http://developer.android.com/design/handhelds/index.html</a></p>

<p>Android&rsquo;s system UI provides the framework on top of which you build your app, whether you&rsquo;re designing for phones, tablets, watches, or other form factors. Aspects of UI that are especially important for phones and tablets include the Home screen experience, global device navigation, and notifications.</p>

<p>Your app will play an important part in keeping the overall Android experience consistent and enjoyable to use. This page introduces some of the main elements that can help you achieve this goal. The main Android Design topics listed on the left, after the Devices sections, provide detailed guidelines for phones and tablets.</p>

<h2>Home, All Apps, and Recents</h2>

<h3>Home screen</h3>

<p>Home is a customizable space that houses app shortcuts, folders and widgets. Navigate between different home screen panels by swiping left and right.</p>

<p>The Favorites Tray at the bottom always keeps your most important shortcuts and folders in view regardless of which panel is currently showing.</p>

<p>Access the entire collection of apps and widgets by touching the All Apps button at the center of the Favorites Tray.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ui_overview_home_screen.png" alt="ui_overview_home_screen" /></p>

<h3>All apps screen</h3>

<p>The All Apps screen lets you browse the entire set of apps and widgets that are installed on your device.</p>

<p>Users can drag an app or widget icon from the All Apps screen and place it in any empty location on any Home screen.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ui_overview_all_apps.png" alt="ui_overview_all_apps" /></p>

<h3>Recents screen</h3>

<p>Recents provides an efficient way of switching between recently used applications. It provides a clear navigation path between multiple ongoing tasks.</p>

<p>The Recents button at the right side of the navigation bar displays the apps that the user has interacted with most recently. They are organized in reverse chronological order with the most recently used app at the bottom.</p>

<p>Switch to an app by touching it. Remove an item by swiping left or right.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ui_overview_recents.png" alt="ui_overview_recents" /></p>

<h2>System Bars</h2>

<p>The system bars are screen areas dedicated to the display of notifications, communication of device status, and device navigation. Typically the system bars are displayed concurrently with your app. Apps that display immersive content, such as movies or images, can temporarily hide the system bars to allow the user to enjoy full screen content without distraction.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ui_overview_system_ui.png" alt="ui_overview_system_ui" /></p>

<h4>1. Status Bar</h4>

<p>Displays pending notifications on the left and status, such as time, battery level, or signal strength, on the right. Swipe down from the status bar to show notification details.</p>

<h4>2. Navigation Bar</h4>

<p>New for phones in Android 4.0, the navigation bar is present only on devices that don&rsquo;t have the traditional hardware keys. It houses the device navigation controls Back, Home, and Recents, and also displays a menu for apps written for Android 2.3 or earlier.</p>

<h2>Notifications</h2>

<p>Notifications are brief messages that users can access at any time from the status bar. They provide updates, reminders, or information that&rsquo;s important, but not critical enough to warrant interrupting the user. Open the notifications drawer by swiping down on the status bar. Touching a notification opens the associated app.</p>

<p>Notifications can be expanded to uncover more details and relevant actions. When collapsed, notifications have a one-line title and a one-line message.The recommended layout for a notification includes two lines. If necessary, you can add a third line.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ui_overview_notifications.png" alt="ui_overview_notifications" /></p>

<p>Swiping a notification right or left removes it from the notification drawer.</p>

<p><img src="/images/notifications_dismiss.png" alt="notifications_dismiss" /></p>

<h2>Common App UI</h2>

<p>A typical Android app uses action bars, and many apps will include a navigation drawer.<br/>
一个典型的 Android 应用包含 Action Bar 和 Content Area 两部分。如果应用的结构较复杂，可以使用 Navigation Drawer 来切换主要页面。</p>

<p><img src="/images/app_structure_drawer.png" alt="app_structure_drawer" /></p>

<h4>Action Bar</h4>

<p>The command and control center for your app. The action bar surfaces the most important actions for the current view, and may include simple controls for switching between views.</p>

<h4>Navigation Drawer</h4>

<p>If your app&rsquo;s structure is more complex, the navigation drawer can display the main navigation options. The navigation drawer expands from the left edge of the screen, overlaying the content area but not the action bar.</p>

<h4>Content Area</h4>

<p>The space where the content of your app is displayed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[置顶]Android文章归类]]></title>
    <link href="http://xuanxi.github.io/blog/2014/07/14/zhi-ding-androidwen-zhang-gui-lei/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-14T00:21:05+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://xuanxi.github.io/blog/2014/07/14/zhi-ding-androidwen-zhang-gui-lei</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://blog.xuanxi.me/blog/2014/07/14/guan-fang-wen-dang-yue-du-yu-zong-jie/">官方文档阅读与总结</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android Design Principles]]></title>
    <link href="http://xuanxi.github.io/blog/2014/07/13/android-design-principles/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-13T22:13:04+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://xuanxi.github.io/blog/2014/07/13/android-design-principles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>原文地址：<a href="http://developer.android.com/design/get-started/principles.html">http://developer.android.com/design/get-started/principles.html</a></p>

<p>推荐应用：<br/>
<a href="http://www.any.do/">Any.do</a></p>

<p>These design principles were developed by and for the Android User Experience Team to keep user&rsquo;s best interests in mind.For Android developers and designers,they continue to underline the more detailed design guidelines for different types of devices.<br/>
Consider these principles as you apply your own creativity and design thinking.Deviate with purpose.<br/>
以下设计准则由Android用户体验团队秉承用户利益至上的原则开发。当你发挥自己的创造力和思考的时候，请将它们纳入考虑之中，并有意识地加以实践。</p>

<h2><em>Enchant ME</em></h2>

<p><em>迷住我</em></p>

<h3>Delight me in surprising ways</h3>

<p>以意想不到的方式取悦我</p>

<p>A beautiful surface,a carefully-places animation,or a well-timed sound effect is a joy to experience. Subtle effects contribute to a feeling of effortlessness and a sense that a powerful force is at hand.<br/>
一个漂亮的界面，一个悉心摆放的动画，或者一个适时的声音效果，都是一种快乐的体验。精细的效果能产生一种轻松的氛围，感觉手中有一股强大可控的力量。</p>

<p><img src="/images/principles_delight.png" alt="principles_delight" /></p>

<h3>Real objects are more fun than buttons and menus</h3>

<p>真实对象比按钮和菜单更加有趣</p>

<p>Allow people to directly touch and manipulate objects in your app. It reduces the cognitive effort needed to perform a task while making it more emotionally satisfying.<br/>
允许人们直接触摸和操作你应用中的对象。它减少了执行一项任务所需的认识上的力量，并使之更加令人舒心。</p>

<p><img src="/images/principles_real_objects.png" alt="principles_real_objects" /></p>

<h3>Let me make it mine</h3>

<p>让我把它变成我的</p>

<p>People love to add personal touches because it helps them feel at home and in control. Provide sensible, beautiful defaults, but also consider fun, optional customizations that don&rsquo;t hinder primary tasks.<br/>
人们喜欢加入个人手势，因为这让他们感觉自在与可控。提供可感的、漂亮的默认手势，但同时又考虑好玩、可选又不影响主要任务的定制项。</p>

<p><img src="/images/principles_make_it_mine.png" alt="principles_make_it_mine" /></p>

<h3>Get to know me</h3>

<p>学会了解我</p>

<p>Learn peoples' preferences over time. Rather than asking them to make the same choices over and over, place previous choices within easy reach.<br/>
随着时间的推移，学习用户的偏好。不要反复地问用户同样的问题，将用户先前的选择列出来以供快捷选择。</p>

<p><img src="/images/principles_get_to_know_me.png" alt="principles_get_to_know_me" /></p>

<h2><em>Simplify My Life</em></h2>

<p><em>简化我的生活</em></p>

<h3>Keep it brief</h3>

<p>用语简洁</p>

<p>Use short phrases with simple words. People are likely to skip sentences if they&rsquo;re long.<br/>
使用由简单词汇构成的短句。人们更倾向于跳过过长的句子。</p>

<p><img src="/images/principles_keep_it_brief.png" alt="principles_keep_it_brief" /></p>

<h3>Pictures are faster than words</h3>

<p>图像比文字更能直达理解</p>

<p>Consider using pictures to explain ideas. They get people&rsquo;s attention and can be much more efficient than words.<br/>
考虑使用图像来解释观点。图像能捕获人们的注意力，往往比文字更有效率。</p>

<p><img src="/images/principles_pictures.png" alt="principles_pictures" /></p>

<h3>Decide for me but let me have the final say</h3>

<p>为我决定，但最终由我说了算</p>

<p>Take your best guess and act rather than asking first. Too many choices and decisions make people unhappy. Just in case you get it wrong, allow for &lsquo;undo&rsquo;.<br/>
做最好的猜测，先做而非先问。太多的选择和决定会令人不愉。只当你可能会犯错时，才提供个‘撤消’，然后仍然先做后问。</p>

<p><img src="/images/principles_decide_for_me.png" alt="principles_decide_for_me" /></p>

<h3>Only show what I need when I need it</h3>

<p>只在我需要的时候显示我所要的</p>

<p>People get overwhelmed when they see too much at once. Break tasks and information into small, digestible chunks. Hide options that aren&rsquo;t essential at the moment, and teach people as they go.<br/>
当一下子看到太多东西时，人们容易受打击。将任务和信息分解成小的、可消化的片段。隐藏当前非必须的选项，并指导人们如何走下去。</p>

<p><img src="/images/principles_information_when_need_it.png" alt="principles_information_when_need_it" /></p>

<h3>I should always know where I am</h3>

<p>我应该总能知道我在哪里</p>

<p>Give people confidence that they know their way around. Make places in your app look distinct and use transitions to show relationships among screens. Provide feedback on tasks in progress.<br/>
给人们以清楚自己在哪的信心。把你应用中的不同场景设计得可区分，并使用变换效果来显示不同场景（窗口）之间的关系。提供任务进度反馈。</p>

<p><img src="/images/principles_navigation.png" alt="principles_navigation" /></p>

<h3>Never lose my stuff</h3>

<p>决不能丢失我的东西</p>

<p>Save what people took time to create and let them access it from anywhere. Remember settings, personal touches, and creations across phones, tablets, and computers. It makes upgrading the easiest thing in the world.<br/>
保存用户花时间创建的东西，使得他们能随处访问。跨手机、平板电脑及计算机等平台，记住设置、个人手势以及作品。这将使得软件升级成为世界上最简单的事。</p>

<p><img src="/images/principles_never_lose_stuff.png" alt="principles_never_lose_stuff" /></p>

<h3>If it looks the same, it should act the same</h3>

<p>如果看起来一样，所做的事就该一样</p>

<p>Help people discern functional differences by making them visually distinct rather than subtle. Avoid modes, which are places that look similar but act differently on the same input.<br/>
通过在视觉上加以区别，来帮助人们区分出功能的差异来。避免出现雷同场景，即看上去一样，但对于同一输入结果不同的场景。</p>

<p><img src="/images/principles_looks_same.png" alt="principles_looks_same" /></p>

<h3>Only interrupt me if it&rsquo;s important</h3>

<p>只在十分重要时打断我</p>

<p>Like a good personal assistant, shield people from unimportant minutiae. People want to stay focused, and unless it&rsquo;s critical and time-sensitive, an interruption can be taxing and frustrating.<br/>
尤如一个好的个人助理，应该保护上司不被不重要的小事打扰。人们需要专注，除非情况十分严重并且紧急，打扰会是十分令人不悦的。</p>

<p><img src="/images/principles_important_interruption.png" alt="principles_important_interruption" /></p>

<h2><em>Make Me Amazing</em></h2>

<p><em>让我惊讶</em></p>

<h3>Give me tricks that work everywhere</h3>

<p>给我点处处可行的诀窍</p>

<p>People feel great when they figure things out for themselves. Make your app easier to learn by leveraging visual patterns and muscle memory from other Android apps. For example, the swipe gesture may be a good navigational shortcut.<br/>
人们如果能够自己探索出东西来，将会兴奋不已。通过使用可视的模式和习惯操作，使你的应用更加易于学习。比如，猛击操作会是一个很好的导航快捷手势。</p>

<p><img src="/images/principles_tricks.png" alt="principles_tricks" /></p>

<h3>It&rsquo;s not my fault</h3>

<p>这不是我的错</p>

<p>Be gentle in how you prompt people to make corrections. They want to feel smart when they use your app. If something goes wrong, give clear recovery instructions but spare them the technical details. If you can fix it behind the scenes, even better.<br/>
在提示用户改正错误时，应该礼貌。他们在用你应用的时候，需要被认为是聪明的。如果出错了，给出明确的恢复指令，而不是将技术细节留给他们。如果你可以在后台修复错误，那当然最好。</p>

<p><img src="/images/principles_error.png" alt="principles_error" /></p>

<h3>Sprinkle encouragement</h3>

<p>挥洒鼓励</p>

<p>Break complex tasks into smaller steps that can be easily accomplished. Give feedback on actions, even if it&rsquo;s just a subtle glow.<br/>
将复杂的任务分解成小的容易被完成的步骤。对用户的操作给出反馈，即使只是一小步的成功。</p>

<p><img src="/images/principles_sprinkle_encouragement.png" alt="principles_sprinkle_encouragement" /></p>

<h3>Do the heavy lifting for me</h3>

<p>为我担负重任</p>

<p>Make novices feel like experts by enabling them to do things they never thought they could. For example, shortcuts that combine multiple photo effects can make amateur photographs look amazing in only a few steps.<br/>
通过使他们做成他们认为自己不可能做到的事，让新手感觉自己像专家一样。比如，综合多个照片效果的快捷操作可使得外行简单几步做出惊人的照片效果来。</p>

<p><img src="/images/principles_heavy_lifting.png" alt="principles_heavy_lifting" /></p>

<h3>Make important things fast</h3>

<p>让重要的事情能更快地完成</p>

<p>Not all actions are equal. Decide what&rsquo;s most important in your app and make it easy to find and fast to use, like the shutter button in a camera, or the pause button in a music player.<br/>
并非所有的操作都是平等的。确定你应用中最重要的操作，使它能很容易地被发现与使用，比如相机上的快门，又如音乐播放器上的暂停按钮。</p>

<p><img src="/images/principles_make_important_fast.png" alt="principles_make_important_fast" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
